Guide to the Herbert Resnicow Papers RG.024
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Herbert Resnicow Papers
1983-1996
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
RG.024
8 Cubic Feet 8 cartons
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Herbert Resnicow in 2016, on behalf of the Estate of Melly Resnicow.
- Series I: Uncorrected Proofs (bound)
  - Murder Across and Down: A Crossword Puzzle Mystery (2 copies), 1985 June (Box 1)
  - Murder at the Super Bowl (2 copies), 1986 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Curse: A Whodunit, 1986 (Box 1)
- Series II: Published Monographs (U.S. editions)
  - The Gold Solution: A Whodunit, 1983 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Deadline: A Whodunit, 1984 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Frame: A Whodunit, 1984 (Box 1)
  - The Seventh Crossword, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Murder Across and Down, 1985 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Curse: A Whodunit, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Murder at the Super Bowl (Fran Tarkenton and Herb Resnicow), 1986 (Box 1)
  - The Crossword Code, 1986 (Box 1)
  - The Crossword Legacy, 1987 (Box 1)
  - The Crossword Hunt, 1987 (Box 1)
  - The Dead Room, 1987 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Gamble: A Mystery, 1988 (Box 1)
  - The Hot Place: A Mystery, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Murder at City Hall (Edward Koch and Resnicow), 1995 (Box 1)
- Series III: Published Monographs (International editions)
  - The Gold Solution (British edition), 1984 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Deadline (British edition), 1985 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Frame (British edition), 1986 (Box 1)
  - Il Grande Gold (Italian edition), 1984 (Box 1)
  - Cruciverba con Delitto (Italian edition), 1986 (Box 1)
  - Cruciverba per un Codice (Italian edition), 1987 (Box 1)
  - Camera con Morto (Italian edition), 1988 (Box 1)
  - Il Settimo Cruciverba (Italian edition), 1988 (Box 1)
  - Caccia al Cruciverba (Italian edition), 1989 (Box 1)
  - The Dead Room (Japanese edition), 1990 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Solution (Japanese edition), undated
  - The Gold Deadline (Japanese edition), undated (Box 1)
- Series IV: Loose manuscripts (in boxes)
  - Herbert Resnicow's "The Dark Room" and Herb Aaron's "Diamond in the Dead Room", undated (Box 1)
  - The Gold Solution (annotated draft), undated (Box 2, Item 1)
  - The Gold Solution (copy edited), undated (Box 2, Item 2)
  - The Gold Solution (with corrections), undated (Box 2, Item 3)
  - The Gold Solution (photocopied edits), undated (Box 2, Item 4)
  - The Gold Solution: A Whodunit (photocopied edits), undated (Box 2, Item 5)
  - The Gold Solution (photocopied edits), undated (Box 2, Item 6)
  - The Gold Solution (photocopied edits), undated (Box 3, Item 1)
  - The Gold Deadline, undated (Box 3, Item 2)
  - The Gold Curse, undated (Box 3, Item 3)
  - The Gold Curse (in paper bag with note and edits from editor), 1986 July 29 (Box 3, Item 4)
  - The Gold Curse (corrected manuscript and note from St. Martin's Press editor), 1985 October 10 (Box 3, Item 5)
  - The Gold Gamble (with notes in brown paper), undated (Box 3, Item 6)
  - The Gold Gamble (final manuscript), Red Card (plot summary), and letter from Resnicow to editors (in brown paper), 1987 November 25 (Box 4, Item 1)
  - The Crossword Code, undated (Box 4, Item 2)
  - The Crossword Code (in brown paper), undated (Box 4, Item 3)
  - The Seventh Crossword (draft, galleys corrected by Resnicow, and "KCD's copy" in brown paper), 1986 (Box 4, Item 4)
  - The Seventh Crossword (galleys), undated (Box 4, Item 5)
  - The Seventh Crossword (galleys, master, and drafts), undated (Box 4, Item 6)
  - The Crossword Legacy (galleys with notes in brown paper), 1986 (Box 5, Item 1)
  - The Crossword Legacy (in brown paper), undated (Box 5, Item 2)
  - The Crossword Hunt (author galleys with note from editors in brown paper), 1987 (Box 5, Item 3)
  - The Crossword Hunt (in brown paper), undated (Box 5, Item 4)
  - A Killing at the Super Bowl (draft), undated (Box 5, Item 5)
  - Murder at the World Series (Resnicow and Tom Seaver draft), 1987 (Box 5, Item 6)
  - Diamond in the Dead Room draft, undated (Box 5, Item 7)
  - The Al Baer Series and The Dead Room (Plot Summary), undated (Box 5, Item 8)
  - The Dead Room (in brown paper), undated (Box 6, Item 1)
  - The Dead Room (in brown paper), undated (Box 6, Item 2)
  - The Red Card (drafts, written with Pele), undated (Box 6, Item 3)
  - Die Laughing (a Marcy Gabor mystery), 1993 (Box 6, Item 4)
  - The Spy in My Bed (with loose notes), 1988 (Box 6, Item 5)
  - The Crossword Trap (oversize in brown paper), undated (Box 7, Item 1)
  - Beanball (oversize in brown paper), undated (Box 7, Item 2)
  - Beanball, undated (Box 7, Item 3)
  - The Hot Place (with note from St. Martin's Press editor), 1990 May 7 (Box 7, Item 4)
  - The Hot Place (original manuscript with not from St. Martin's Press editor), 1990 November 27 (Box 6, Item 3)
  - The Case of the Missing Max (And Other Stories), 1994 (Box 7, Item 6)
  - The Gold Curse (oversize in brown paper), undated (Box 7, Item 7)
  - Mixed drafts including "The World's Greatest Architect: A short story", undated
- Series V: Short Stories and Screenplays, undated
  - Head Up, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - True Witness, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - A Few Stories for Mitzi, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Odds, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - D.W.I., 1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - The Christmas Bear, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Sub Rosa, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Typecasting, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Good Act, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Filial Gifts, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Greater Love Than This..., 1987 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - The Avenger, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Problem: Macy's Window, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Problem: Macy's Window, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Dog Act, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Deconstruction, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - The Records Left, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Anarch, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Nosim, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - The Third Conflict, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - The Whodunit List, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Fatal Oversights, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Fairy Godfather, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Greater Love Than This... (with Alfred Hitchcock Mystery Magazine rejection letter), 1996 October 23 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Die Laughing Screenplay, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Die Laughing Screenplay, 4th draft, 1994 June 21 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Series VI: Notes and Galleys
  - The Crossword Trap, Notes and Letter, 1968 December 20 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Red Card draft, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Super Bowl galleys, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 7th Crossword, notes in spiral notebook, undated (Box 10, Item 1)
  - Seventh Crossword, notes in spiral notebook, undated (Box 10, Item 2)
  - Gold Curse I, notes in spiral notebook, undated (Box 11, Item 1)
  - Gold Curse II, notes in spiral notebook, undated (Box 11, Item 2)
  - Rules, notes in spiral notebook, undated (Box 11, Item 3)
  - The Crossword Legacy I, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Crossword Legacy II, undated (Box 12, Item 2)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 12, Item 3)